<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="86"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Puducherry Technological University





                 ExprEssions










































































                   31             Years     The Literary Club                                   MAY



                                                                                                2022
                                            Cogito, ergo sum]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[THE LITERARY CLUB








                                                 OUR VISION

                                   To provide a conducive platform for expression of

                                      varied ideas and perspectives and encourage


                                    holistic development while celebrating diversity

                                                  OUR MISSION

                               To help the students identify and hone their unique skills.


                           To collaborate with various organizations to expand opportunities.

                                    To familiarize the students with a wide spectrum

                                           of issues and promote discussions.

                                  To sensitize the students on the challenges faced by

                                   society and create a sense of social responsibility.]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Contents






                 Message from the Vice-Chancellor .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  . 6


                 Message from the Registrar  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  8

                 Message from the Dean (Students)  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  10


                 Message from the Dean (A&IC) .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  11

                 A Note from the Convenor .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  12


                 Faculty Co-ordinators Say  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  14

                 From the Editorial Team  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  16




                Articles



                 Passion for Change.  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  . 19

                 Value of Time . .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  . 20


                 Pondicherry Engineering College  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  . 22

                 Curioso and the Art of Political Expression .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  . 24


                 Home: Here or there? .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .   .  .  .  .  .  .  .  26

                 The Lies .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .   .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  29


                 Pondicherry – where time takes a break!   .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  . 30

                 The Demise of Uniqueness .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  32


                 Body Shaming - The Setbacks and Motivation of a Common

                 Man.  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  34

                 A Look into the Book .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  . 36


                 Depp Vs Heard and the Incessant Stream of Opinions .  .   38

                 Borders  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  . 40


                 The Spiral or a Circle  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  42








                                                                                        Expressions '22      3]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Contents






                 Draupadi - A Feminist View .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  43


                 A New Kid in the Town  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  44

                 Antidote to Suicide  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  47


                 The Life of an NCC Cadet   .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  50

                 The Dictionary   .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  52


                 My Mom's Pep-talk .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .   .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  54

                 After Lockdown Experience  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  56


                 Time  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  . 57

                 Teenage Desires  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  58







                Poems



                 Dreams  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  60


                 Love and Music   .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  62

                 Risk  . .  . .  .  .  .  . .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  63


                 The Mechanics of Life .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  . 64

                 Depression .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  66


                 Becoming a Parent .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .   67

                 Where's Mom?  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  68


                 Greed or Grace   .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  69

                 So says the satellite  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  70


                 Voice of my Soul .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  . 71











                                                                                        Expressions '22   4]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Contents





                 Artwork



                 College Farewell  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  . 73

                 3D Art .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  74


                 Independence Day .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  75

                 Solitude .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  76


                 Moon Knight  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  77

                 The Cow  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  78


                 She .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  79

                 The Lion   .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  80


                 The Peacock  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .  .81





                 Gallery














































                                                                                        Expressions '22      5]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Message from the Vice-Chancellor







                                                          I  am  very glad  to  know  that  the Literary  Club

                                                          of Puducherry Technological  University  has

                                                          come out with another edition of its customary
                                                          publication.

                                                          My warm wishes  to all the stakeholders  for

                                                          bringing out this publication and for providing

                       Dr. S. Mohan                       a platform for airing the expressions  of the
                       Vice-Chancellor                    students of this institute. The sharing of ideas and


                                                          discussions on topics critical to the development
                                                          of the  nation and the global community  as a

                                                          whole are quintessential to the development of

                                                          holistic technocrats and professionals.

                                                          I am happy to note that the Literary Club has

                                                          been an active initiator and catalyst in sparking
                                                          discussions among the students, bringing about





          6     Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[new ideas and challenging the students to give

             some thought  about  the challenges  faced by

             society and meaningful ways to address them.

             I have also been informed that the Literary Club

             has crossed three decades of spirited debate and
             inclusive discussion. The success of a democracy

             depends on active participation by the populace

             and institutes are the first bastion of democracy.

             Civility  and dignity in public discourse  are traits
             that  need practice and  I  am  glad  that  we  have

             a club that encourages the students to hone their

             skills  in this direction,  by introducing them  to

             various topics across the spectrum. The conduct
             of varsity level competitions on various topics is

             also an encouraging sign of the thriving level of

             discourse among the students.

             My wishes to the team behind ‘EXPRESSIONS’ and

             the conduct of events of the Literary Club, as they
             march on to the golden jubilee of service to this

             institution.










































                                                                                       Expressions '22      7]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Message from the Registrar





                                                           Puducherry  Technological University  has long
                                                           taken pride in encouraging the students to

                                                           challenge existing notions, to dare to question

                                                           the status quo and move the wheels of change

                                                           to bring about effective reforms for the better.
                                                           It gives  me pleasure to note that the Literary
                    Dr. G. Sivaradje                       Club has constantly engaged  the students,
                          Registrar
                                                           providing them with ample opportunities and

                                                           the platform to share  their ‘Expressions’,  an
                                                           appropriate name for a magazine that acts as

                                                           a conduit for the most powerful and effective

                                                           resource known to man, the ideas and views of

                                                           the students. Consistency is not everyone’s cup
                                                           of tea, everyone that is, but the industrious team





          8     Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[at the Literary Club, taking it upon themselves     of the Literary Club and I strongly encourage
             every year, to  ensure  that the students of        the Club to continue on the path of progress,

             this institute have a platform to debate, to        marking and  crossing milestones along  the

             discuss,  to  question and to  ponder over          way.

             questions. What is evolution but the answer
             to the question, why not? I congratulate the

             students and alumni who have contributed

             articles to adorn the pages of this edition of

             Expressions. I  extend  my  congratulations  to
             the team behind the release of this magazine

             and  wish the Literary Club the very best.

             Years go by, but the discussions initiated and

             the bonds forged stand the test of time. The
             students stand to gain a lot from the activities





                                                                                       Expressions '22      9]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Message from the Dean (Students)






                                                              the students have greatly benefitted by their

                                                              participation in the events. They also acquire

                                                              skills  essential  in their professional  fields,
                                                              such as effective communication, leadership

                                                              skills, inter-personal communication skills.

                                                              Further, the club brings out  this magazine

                                                              to provide space for the students’ creativity
                                                              to  blossom.  Various  literary  pieces and
                       Dr. S. Kanmani
                       Dean (Students)                        artworks are showcased in it, sharing it with
                                                              the like-hearted and encouraging others to

         The Literary Club  of  our  University  was          participate.

         started 30 years ago to promote languages,           On the occasion of the club entering into its
         literature and student interactions. Time and        31st year, I congratulate the club convenors,

         again, the club organizes a rich and diverse         student mentors and faculty coordinators for

         array  of  literary  activities such as debates,     all success in their future endeavours.

         declamations, group discussions,  poetry
         writing, short story writing, spell  bee, quiz

         contests, webinars, play  and  many  more.

         Through these activities, the student mentors

         reach out to language and literature lovers
         and try to create a space for sharing emotions

         and thoughts.

         The club has been instrumental in building

         a community of creative, imaginative and
         thoughtful  human  beings. It  has created

         deep awareness  about  several  issues  of

         local and global importance. It sensitizes

         students to react constructively  to disparity
         and  injustice in modern society, inculcate

         socially  desirable  values  such  as empathy

         and cooperation. At the individual  level,



          10    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[Message from the Dean (A&IC)





                                                                  admirer of  the club  and  its encompassing

                                                                  activities,  offering discerning opportunities
                                                                  for the students to  participate, compete,

                                                                  learn and evolve into holistic individuals. It

                                                                  inculcates  confidence, social skills,  values

                                                                  and an egalitarian outlook  among the
                                                                  students across the campus.
                         Dr. Srinivasan E
                  Dean (Alumni & International                    I appreciate the members of the club for the
                           Collaboration)                         stellar efforts put in to bring out the magazine


                                                                  and setting a new benchmark.
             The difficult pandemic times are behind us.
                                                                  Wishing you all the very best.
             There can't be a better time to get together

             and celebrate our maverick ideas, creative
             thinking  and intellectual musings.  Rightly,

             the Literary Club of our University is bringing

             out its most awaited annual edition of

             Expressions.
             I have been a keen follower and an ardent





                                                                                       Expressions '22     11]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[A Note from the Convenor





                                           The glory of expression  began 31 years ago - the birth of

                                           the Literary Club of PEC. A seed was planted with passion,
                                           the seed of voices yearning to articulate and be heard. The

                                           sapling was fondly nurtured through the years, and now the

                                           tree is rooted firmly, ensuring shade and shelter. This three-
                                           decade-long history, legacy, and tradition have been fondly

                                           nourished by individual and collective talent. Sailing rough seas

                                           and traversing uneven terrain, we have overcome challenges

                                           because of a sense of solidarity and oneness the Literary Club

                                           fraternity always fostered. We stand at the threshold of a new
                                           era of growth as the transition to  PTU beckons a future of
             Dr. Shanthi Simon
                  Convenor,                hopes and aspirations to scale greater heights.
              The Literary Club
                                           The beautiful moments of yesterday are the beautiful memories

                                           of today. We keep creating memories for our tomorrow. After

                                           an unexpectedly long stint on the virtual platform, we are back
                                           in  physical  space to celebrate a milestone,  the completion

                                           of three decades in the long, eventful journey of the club.




          12    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[Anyone with a passion for reading, writing,           This is also the time for all of us to reflect, to

             and speaking  is  always welcome  to share            dream, to deliberate and to share.  We re-
             this platform created for open deliberations.         dedicate ourselves to the mission of sending

             Respecting individuality while inculcating a          forth competent professionals and sensitized

             spirit of camaraderie, all stakeholders move          humans as ambassadors of change. We stay

             forward with unrelenting  enthusiasm  and             united in our efforts

             uncompromising standards  of  thought  and                “To see a world in a grain of sand
             action.
                                                                        And a heaven in a wild flower,
             We celebrate differences  and  hence
                                                                    Hold infinity in the palm of (our) hands
             encourage debates  and  discussions.  An
                                                                           And eternity in an hour”.
             unquenchable thirst for expressions  that
                                                                   Let us carry this message forward:
             spills out in the form of creative interactions
                                                                         “We think therefore we are”.
             forms the very essence  of the club. The
             mentors work  hard  to  promote  the  club’s          Hats off to the editorial team of Najmu, Rahul,

             ethos - diversity and  differences  brought           Tarun and special thanks to RamVignesh, for

             together in an open forum where adulations            the untiring and meticulous efforts they have
             and critiques catalyse an in-depth probe into         put in to give colour and form to the varied

             oneself.  All the initiators and torchbearers of      expressions.

             this movement have a significant role in this         Wish you all the very best.

             journey.



                                                                                       Expressions '22     13]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[Faculty Coordinators say







                                                        It is a great honor and pleasure to be a part of

                                                        the Literary Club of Puducherry Technological

                                                        University.

                                                        The Literary Club organizes  a rich  and diverse

                                                        array of literary activities every year. The activities
                                                        culminate with the PTU’s flagship Literary Annual

                                                        Festival - Curioso.  The club provides a forum for

                                                        the students to acquire highly  valued skills,  such

                                                        as effective communication, leadership skills, team
                         Dr. V. Akila
                     Asst. Professor, CSE               work,  interpersonal communication skills  and
                                                        persuasive skills. The club also has been functioning

                                                        continuously for the past thirty years.  I would like

                                                        to convey my best wishes on the occasion of the
                                                        release of this year’s magazine.





          14    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[and  meticulous efforts in endeavoring to

                                                                   bring out  the magazine. At this juncture, I

                                                                   would exhort all students to partake in the
                                                                   various activities being conducted by the Club

                                                                   zealously thereby sharpening and polishing

                                                                   their skills. I hope this initiative of unearthing

                                                                   the writing prowess of students continues in
                                                                   the coming years.  My best wishes  to one

                           Ms. S. Geetha                           and all. I hope that more students contribute
                        Asst. Professor, HSS
                                                                   their mitght to the growth of the club in the

             It is gratifying to learn that the Literary Club      coming days.

             of PTU is bringing out  “EXPRESSIONS”, a

             magazine that seeks to provide a platform
             for students to pen their thoughts on anything

             that is close to their hearts. On this occasion,

             I would like to appreciate the efforts of the

             students in giving shape to  their ideas by

             utilizing this magazine to express themselves
             and  articulate  their ideas. Academic

             Development doesn’t  mean only  acquiring

             degrees  but rather it lies  in  developing
             one’s skills,  which are a prerequisite for

             an  individual’s holistic grooming  for  the

             future. The Literary Club provides ample

             opportunities for students to partake in

             activities like Group  Discussions,  debates,
             extempore and the like  thereby enabling

             the students’ acquisition of soft skills  and

             communication  skills.  It is a fact that the
             Literary Club serves as a forum for students to

             come out of their shell and interact with their

             peers without any inhibitions. It would only

             be in the fitness of things to compliment the

             team of the Literary Club for their painstaking



                                                                                       Expressions '22     15]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[From the Editorial Team





         The Literary Club: A Realm of its Own




        The journey  of life  takes many interesting          The Literary Club, fresh  off of completing

        twists and  turns. The voyage  is never               three decades since its founding  and
        smooth, but it always has its moments. Every          marching  towards the milestone  of 50

        individual entering this Institute has a unique       years, has provided the environment where

        story, with trials  and tribulations, joys and        discussions  flourish,  ideas emerge  and

        jubilations… Everyone embarks on a journey            change  materialises.  The lore  of the club
        of  self-discovery,  and  emerge on  the  other       involves  several anecdotes where groups

        side older, wiser and with the scars and stars        of  students  and  bunches of  misfits band

        to show for it.                                       together to create something new, something

        Upon entering the institute, fresh out of school      fresh  and something daring… Something

        and waiting to begin the experience of the            which  others might try to emulate, might
        ever-hyped “College life”, the students are           try to continue and might try to turn into a

        greeted into the institute with an introduction       legacy.

        to  the various activities  and way of life on        The club has chugged along, with every batch

        campus, and one club in particular…                   of students bringing new ideas to the table.
                                                              Seamless transitions and flawless planning,


          16    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[followed by impeccable stage management               the stage, a moment for which they braved

             and the backing of a Convenor minted out              the odds and participated with full fervour.

             of gold, we were inducted and were off to a           “Persevere  and strive  to achieve  your

             good start. One and a half blissful years of          goals” is  a statement often used, like  all
             offline events and then the pandemic struck.          other statements, profound  with meaning

             Amidst the reign of pandemonium and                   but seldom  followed with action. That was

             uncertainty, the mentors of the club took it          the norm we, as human beings have been

             upon themselves to ensure that the students           accustomed to from the time, we knew that
             had an outlet for their creativity, a canvas for      integrity and  expectation is something to

             their art, a platform to share their expressions      be had in an ideal world. In reality, Ideality

             and a stage to display their talents, a safe          doesn’t exist.

             haven for the Inquisitive and the Curious.            The Literary Club taught us that ideality isn’t

             Back on campus after nearly two  years of             necessary to work wonders… As long as a
             online learning, the rich traditions of the club      gang of misfits  come  together to debate,

             needed execution  and  our  batch  stepped            discuss, argue, gaggle and ponder over the

             up to the task. By the time  this  magazine           questions of importance, and they encourage

             is  released,  Literary Day 2022 would be             the students of this institute to engage in civil
             underway and the participants and winners             discussions and helping them on their path

             of CURIOSO 2022 will have their moment on             to self-discovery!




                                                                                       Expressions '22     17]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[A
                                                 rticles]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[such  example is  the Formula 1 pit stops. In

                                                                motorsports, a pit stop is a pause or a break

                                                                at a designated area (“pit”) by a car during a

                                                                race. During this stop, the vehicle undergoes
                                                                tire changes, repairs, and  other mechanical

                                                                adjustments managed by a pit crew. While the

                                                                spotlight is usually on the drivers and engineers

                                                                but the members of the pit crew who are the

                     AROUNKUMAR M                               driving force remain to be the unsung heroes.
                   1993 - 97, Mechanical                        This has gone through a rapid transformation

                   Sr. Specialist, Vestas Wind                  from 60.5 sec in 1950 to 2.7 sec in 2013 to
                  Manufacturing A/s, Denmark
                                                                1.8 sec at present.

        Passion for Change                                      As a student, we need to get ourselves prepared
                                                                to undertake a significant  transformation, be

                                                                passionate about improvement and be in line
        Today, all  businesses  are challenged  to
                                                                with the change. This passion of change is
        keep pace with the changes  in  the business
                                                                need of the hour.
        environment.  Rapid changes  in technology
                                                                Link to videos: https://youtu.be/LzBlnfgeOZ0
        have put  immense pressure on  the life cycle

        of products which has led to once very stable

        businesses  becoming tycoons.  This puts

        pressure  on the management to reflect  and
        analyse if their organization is using tomorrow’s

        money for solving yesterday’s problems and

        immediately take corrective measures to make
        sure the money is made  available for  future

        growth and survival.

        Alternatively, companies may want to look at

        the ongoing benefits of creating a work culture

        where employees at every level of the company

        are engaged  in improving the supply  chain,
        and thereby enhance the customer experience.

        You can see how extensively  the market has

        improved,  be  it  products  or  services.  One




                                                                                       Expressions '22     19]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[Value of Time




                                           One of the most important gifts for life, time! Learn to enjoy

                                           every  minute of your life... but how do you enjoy? Just

                                            entertainment? True, college life is the best part of our life, in
                                            fact the happiest one, with different kinds of experiences that

                                            we carry in our memory lifelong. And this comes to fruition

                                            only if we are able to manage fun and studies hand in hand.

                                            The two areas most students struggle to attune to college life

                                            are studies and enjoyment.  When they receive this newfound

                                            freedom, they are unable to manage themselves, tempting
                                            them to traverse through the wrong path and then finding it

               Susmitha Padman              difficult to take a U-turn. Think before you take any new step
                 1993 - 97, Civil
           Planning and Cost Estimate,      in life!
               Engineer, Petrofac           Time management is a solid foundation for success in life

                     (Kuwait)               and that is where some college students fail to realise that
             Maths & French Tutor
                                            what they do today determines their tomorrows.

                                            Faking attendance, completing your friends’  assignments,


          20    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[saving  friends  from punishments,  teasing           is important for you and start implementing

             each other, nick names, all are an inseparable        it.  Slowly but  gradually,  you  find that  your

             part of college life. Enjoy while they last! But      mind takes you to the way that fetches you
             don’t forget that these few years are the years       more happiness and success. Try taking up

             that determine who you are tomorrow. Most             internships  during your vacation for better

             students dabble their way through life, never         learning experience. All these should be done
             deciding to  master anything in particular.           but not at the cost of missing out having fun

             College years is the right time to  learn to          with friends.

             develop growth mindset, seek  challenges,             The gossips in the canteen, the never-ending

             get feedback, respond resiliently to setbacks,        fun in the hostel rooms which is one of the

             focus on what actually you want to be. Follow         crucial places for self-development, the days
             your passion and find all possible  ways              you took to gather courage to express your

             to  improve them.  The commitments and                love to your love bird will be the subject of talk

             determination that you have now will lead to          during your reunion days that add laughter,
             flexible and relaxed life at your later age.          fun and frolic. Stay positive, Enjoy Life!


             Plan your days, it is paramount to know what



                                                                                       Expressions '22     21]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[Pondicherry Engineering College






                                           On this sunny spring morning of 10th May 2022, I am lost

                                           in my own thoughts  looking out  of the window, reflecting
                                           about  my time as an out-of-state student enrolled in a

                                           Bachelor of Technology Degree program  at  Pondicherry

                                           Engineering  College (PEC), Tamil Nadu,  India. Here  is my
                                           story: I was ambitious, impatient, eccentric  and arrogant.

                                           I  certainly was brash and  privileged to  make the transition

                                           from very sought after Information Technology (IT) degree to

                                           all feared and bored Electrical  and Electronics  Engineering

                                           (EEE) degree, during the second year, simply because that is
           Yeshasvi Tirupachuri
                2007 - 11, EEE             what I was interested in learning at that  point, despite the
              Roboticist at Agile          jobs and careers this decision would cost me as advised by
          Robots AG, Munich, the           many around me at the time. I worked, maybe not as hard as
            first German Robotics
                    Unicorn                I should have. I played, maybe not as hard as I should have.
                                           But I lived. I lived life on my own terms, made friendships that

                                           are bountiful and shared many meaningful experiences with

                                           incredible human beings. I did get into plenty of trouble such
                                           as a physical confrontation with the rector, or borderline failing


          22    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[a  course I  am  very good  at  just  because I       still ambitious but patient, still eccentric but
             got  bored  and vehemently disagreed with             understanding. The patterns of generosity

             the outdated  teaching methods. I survived            I experienced  as an out-of-state student at

             all of it, partly due to my grit but mostly due       PEC gave me the faith and comfort to seek

             to the generous support and understanding             out similar patterns in faraway lands, and I
             from many around me who have been my                  feel blessed to discover that it is an innate

             invisible  guardian angels, from family and           human nature to be kind  and generous.

             friends to incredibly talented academic staff         To  those who  are curious, eccentric  and

             at PEC from different departments. I stepped          slightly off-the-path, have faith and seek out
             into  PEC  without  having any  clue where,           guidance from people around you. Have an

             what, and how it is.  But I stepped out of            open conversation, be receptive and smile.

             PEC with experiences that bolstered my will

             and character  further  to face  the world in
             realizing what I dream to set out. From being

             one of the first candidates to  secure  a job

             during the on-campus placements in 2010

             to obtaining a world class research training
             in Europe and obtaining a Doctorate Degree

             in 2020, I cherish my time and experiences at

             PEC to be formative and foundational. I am




                                                                                       Expressions '22     23]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[Curioso and the Art of Political Expression




                                           The acclaimed Literary Festival  of Pondicherry Engineering

                                           College (Currently Pondicherry Technological University) has

                                           got several feathers in its cap when it comes to bringing out

                                           hidden talents of students and setting up a non-judgmental
                                           stage for expression. One practice that the forum inadvertently

                                           instilled amongst students is the need to be socio-politically

                                           conscious and the decorum to discuss and accept contradictory
                                           perspectives.


                                           In my freshman year, I was drawn to only creative  writing

               Sai Balaguru G              contests of  curioso since  facing a  gathering  always  left me
                2015 - 19, EEE             anxious and, I hardly had any knowledge to participate in
                    Analyst,               events like Group Discussion, Debate, sell me This Pen, Mayor
                  Deloitte USI
                  Hyderabad                Don’t Vote for me. I was blown by the sheer quality of thought
                                           put forth by participants who had participated in these oral

                                           events. I realized the need to be politically aware so that I get

                                           a chance to compete in these events.

                                           An accusation we come across on Professional  Course



          24    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[students is that they are the least bothered          in events like debates and block & tackle. Any

             on grounds of socially awareness and                  platform that allows a participant to ideate

             their academic curriculum doesn’t  have               for and against a specific  notion facilitates

             the space to  include courses that  touched           the  students to  uphold  the  constitutionally
             upon Anthropology, Sociology, Indian Polity,          provided Freedom of Expression.

             History, Humanities  etc., Curioso through            Curioso has taken up a formidable position in

             infotainment guaranteed  events simplified            democratizing the political expression inside
             this Herculean Task of Engineering students           college  premises  that eventually  enabled

             taking up discussions  on Humanities  and             the  students  to  consume world  politics that

             the ability to convince one’s peers with their        further helped us to face real life scenarios

             articulate words.                                     with necessary discretion.

             Curioso gave me the urge to understand the

             happenings that structured the present socio-
             political realm. Most Importantly it taught us

             to listen to the propositions from both sides of

             spectrum so that we will be able to take part


                                                                                       Expressions '22     25]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[Home: Here or There?






                                           “It’s okay to be scared. Being scared means you’re about to

                                           do something brave.”

                                            On  September 10th, 2021, when  I was at Rajiv  Gandhi
                                            International Airport in Hyderabad, preparing to board my

                                            trip to a foreign continent to continue my higher education,

                                            these were the exact words that ran through my mind. Due to

                                            COVID-19, this journey was an indirect route. I had a 3 day

                                            stay in Egypt for a RTPCR test. I got to see the great pyramids of
                                            Giza and the Nile River! 3 days later, September 13th, 2021,

                    Manish T                I landed in  Toronto Pearson  International Airport, Toronto.
                2016 - 20, EIE              And lo! My bags did not accompany me to the airport. So
            Master of Engineering,
           Electrical and Computer          here I am in a foreign country with no family and few stuff
          Engineering, University of        (only my documents and a spare pair of shorts) had no place
               Windsor, Canada              to stay (my housemates and I had not yet signed the lease to


                                            our apartment)!

                                            My only acquaintance in Toronto was out of town. Then my

                                           senior from university arrived. I would never have been able


          26    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[contracts for  our  house the next day.  The

                                                                   third task had been completed. The following
                                                                   day, I went to my first university class (it was

                                                                   online). Finally, I  ran into two  of my high

                                                                   school buddies and went on a city tour. On

                                                                   my last day in Toronto, I went downtown and

                                                                   roamed about, taking pictures, eating pizza,
                                                                   and sipping beer. Meanwhile, my bags had

                                                                   arrived, and it was time to go for Windsor,

                                                                   my final destination.

                                                                   I reached Windsor on September 18th, 2021.

                                                                   My housemates arrived the following week,
                                                                   and it was a full house. We were six people in

                                                                   a three-bedroom house, and we didn't know

             to  make a  smooth transfer to  Canada  if it         each other! We grew accustomed to each

             hadn't been for this guy.                             other with each passing day. Cooking, eating,

             Moving to Pondicherry for my undergraduate            cleaning, studying, and living together.
             was my first experience living independently,         During the semester I got a few opportunities

             but it was completely  different  this  time          to volunteer at the university and made new

             around. I didn't have  my parents, friends,           friends. Met a group of people to play cricket

             or family within a one-hour flight distance.          with! Hit the gym, found a part time job at an

             Furthermore, the time difference  prevented           IT firm. And my first semester ended just like
             me from calling anyone back home at any               that. I scored great grades!

             time. Let's just say it was a disaster. A cultural    We visited Toronto for NYE, came back, and

             shock, jet lag, and a slew of tasks await me          started the second  semester  and it ended
             as I begin my new life.                               too! During this semester, I got promoted at


             As a result, I developed a to-do list. I began by     my workplace, scored great  grades  again
             taking public transportation and the subway           and went out for a vacation.

             around  Toronto,  then used  Google  Maps             Not everything was easy though. There were

             to find my way to Service Canada, where I             days when  I wished  I was back in India,
             completed my first task in Canada, getting a          among  my family and  friends. Especially

             SIN. Then, with my senior, I went to the phone        when my best friend and uncle died within

             store and completed my second task, getting           a month of each other. I cried; I was sad but

             a SIM. My housemates and I had signed the             there wasn’t much I could do about it. Life


                                                                                       Expressions '22     27]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[here did not wait for me, so I had to move on          country, move cities. All the hostellers reading
        quickly. You don’t even have enough time to            this, you have already done it and you can be

        grieve. The weather is not easy to cope with.          proud of yourself for that.

        Especially after living in southern part of India      Earning and living  independently teaches

        where it is mostly sunny, the absence of sun           you a lot about financial management which
        and  cold temperatures affects you  mentally.          is  generally  a less  spoken topic back in

        Adapting  to  the  new pattern  of  study  is not      Indian households. Working, studying, and

        a  cake walk too.  Plagiarism is an  offence,          running errands for your house teaches  you

        and you get punished severely for it in these          to multitask. Time management - something I
        universities.  For unintended plagiarism, I            learnt by messing up my sleep schedule a lot

        received zero points on two assignments! So,           of times. You also learn to take responsibility

        now I know how to accomplish my work more              of your tasks, especially academic. Lastly, you

        efficiently.                                           learn how simple gestures- a good morning

        As I write this on the flight back home from           from the bus driver, a thank you from your

        Vancouver after my vacations post my second            coffee server,  a  sorry from someone who
        semester, I wonder how Windsor went from               unintentionally blocked your way, make your

        a foreign land to home for me in the past 8            day brighter than usual.

        months!                                                The day you move out of your house to pursue

        Was it because of my senior who first helped me        your life goals is the last day you live in your

        out? Was it because of my efforts to finish tasks      house, and you will never know it. Even if you
        from day one? Was it because I met wonderful           go home for festivals or vacations, you will be

        people  in my house and  my workplace?                 a visitor now. It is a difficult pill to swallow but

        Was it because of  the Canadian  culture of            you will cherish the rewards you get for all the

        welcoming immigrants very friendlily? Maybe            struggles you go through in this phase of life.
        it was a bit of everything. Or maybe it was just

        luck, or maybe it’s just time. Whatever it was,

        I learnt a lot in these few months of staying

        independently in a completely new city without
        any support from known people.


        First, getting things done gives you a boost in
        your confidence that is unparalleled to anything

        else. Secondly, meeting people from different

        culture gives opens up a world of opportunities
        for you. So, move out  of your house. If not



          28    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[his  report card only at the last minute to his
                                                                father with some tears in his eyes and with a

                                                                promise that it won’t happen again. His father

                                                                with a red angry face and in a hurry signed the

                                                                report card. The tears of the boy faded when
                                                                he entered the school gate and he was happy

                                                                again. Days and Years passed and everything

                                                                the boy thought that would end all his miseries

                     Melvino Roshan J                           was a lie he was telling himself. Eventually he
                        2018 -22, ECE                           understood  that  these lies were essential  for

                                                                him because behind all these lies there lies a
        The Lies                                                better part which made him "Happy". You all



                                                                may think that this happiness what he gets is
        Under the blue sky lied a ground filled  with           temporary and eventually he will get another

        children  or I may say scattered all over the           problem soon but why can't we all think that

        empty  ground,  carrying different emotions.            all the problems  which  he  faced were  also

        They were running and playing like that was             temporary and all the lies  were nothing but
        their last day on earth.                                "Hope" which he created to face the problems.

        Among all this drama there was a boy kneeling           Problems  which  we face are temporary too.

        down on the ground hoping all this would end            The question is do we have the hope that all

        soon. He  was being punished  by his  PET sir           our miseries will end and we will be happy. I
        for not wearing proper uniform for school. All          thought writing this article will be a great task

        his thoughts were channeled in one direction            but all I hoped was at the end of the day this

        hoping the PET period would end soon and all            article would help someone to be happy. I don't

        his miseries will come to an end. Finally, the          say hope is a lie but it's good to lie to yourself
        period got over and he went home “Happily”.             to create hope.

        The next day he received his report card with

        poor grades. He didn’t worry about the grades.

        All his thoughts were again channeled in one
        direction on  How  to  get  sign in the  report

        card from his  father. He thought  getting his

        father’s sign would  end  all his miseries.  The

        next day he used the same trick which we all
        used once…yeah you got it right. He revealed



                                                                                       Expressions '22     29]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[Pondicherry – Where Time Takes a Break





                                           The roads laid with near perfect symmetry, vehicles  zig-
                                           zagging with nary a respect for the rules and the knack of

                                           innate understanding with the aid of simple nods of the head,

                                           the trees swaying with branches laden with blossoms giving

                                           the evening sky various hues, the waft of fresh air as one

                                           passes the park, a sense of grandeur and familiarity on seeing
                                           the quintessential orange tinted buildings, the journey through

                                           the street with wonderful street art and craft, discovering new

                                           stores with something unique to offer, in terms of cuisine and
                                           ambience, the salty sea breeze crashing into the faces of the

                   Rahul A P               masses thronging the beach are some of the myriad untold
                2018 - 22, Civil
                                           experiences in Pondicherry.

                                           Just as you are at ease, having spent the better part of the day

                                           visiting the usual haunts, a ride through the winding roads on

                                           the way to Auroville, the dome of irradiance recognized across
                                           the country and the world for its splendor and a constant puzzle


          30    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[to  Pondicherrians.  The clocktower standing         into the rocks, transferring heat to the shore

             tall at the crossroads of two paths, leading to      as they retreat back into the ocean, taking

             the same destination with tolls loud enough          the sand beneath your feet and injecting
             to wake the critters  asleep  in holes  dug in       wind at the back of your sails as you take in

             the sand where the large ice blocks meant            the marvel of this town rich with history and

             to keep produce fresh had been for so long,          diversity.
             the constant buzz of activity on Nehru Street,       Boat  rides and beach trips galore,

             the arterial road of White town, a term with         Pondicherry, christened  with the new name

             connotations worth exploring and discussing          of Puducherry, has long been a window into

             on its merit and continued usage.                    several cultures. To those of you who have

             The night injects a sense of excitement and          the  good  fortune  of  exploring this town

             thrill into this quaint old town.  Streams of        without  any knowledge of its history and
             bright yellow lights  with beam intensities          beauty, shed your fears and inhibitions and

             capable of blinding the uninitiated, the             explore the town with an open mind, you will

             groups of people strolling through the middle        be surprised with the places you find and the

             of the road with all the time in the world to        memories you create!
             discuss that  one thing which might have

             been relegated as a trivial matter anywhere

             else, the waves gaining steam and crashing

                                                                                       Expressions '22     31]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[The Demise of Uniqueness




                                           We live in a society where every person is being pushed into

                                           the so-called community pressure or the social pressure. If we

                                            pause our life for a minute and see, that each and every action

                                            we do are being calculated or judged by an individual or a

                                            group. These kinds of judgements created by the people are
                                            later being translated as the socio pressure. “Herd mentality”

                                            describes a behaviour in which people act the same way or

                                            adopt similar behaviours as the people around them — often
                                            ignoring their own feelings in the process. This affects one’s

                                            individuality and the capability of raising he/she’s opinions
                   Shriram G                over a topic or issue. Individual opinion plays a pivotal role
                 2018 - 22, ECE
                                            in one’s both personal and work life. Herd mentality can be
                                            explained by using a simple example, if a movie is released

                                            when a majority group brands the film as an average one

                                            the remaining people tends to follow it before watching the

                                            film. Opinions changes depending upon their perspectives.



          32    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[Internet has been an easy tool to spread this         their uniqueness. As a  whole we  see that

             herd mentality behaviour among people.                people started to think  on different  ways

             Not everyone has been a prey to this, there           at different times. So unequivocally one’s

             are individuals who think and analyse their           opinion is more important.  We can come

             experiences and opinions on an issue or a             over  the herd mentality by just improving
             problem. We can even see ourselves being              our self-confidence, we must believe that our

             pushed into such kind of situation where we           opinions matter.

             fail to raise  our points, on the other hand

             we just nod to someone  else’s  opinion.
             Each and  everyone’s perspective differ

             but  at the end of the day, it’s just that  we

             make sure that our voices are being heard.

             Uniqueness  the most important  word in
             English it defines how much we are different

             from people to  people;  how  can one lose





                                                                                       Expressions '22     33]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[Body Shaming – The Setbacks and


        Motivation of a Common Man





                                           Have you  ever wondered  what  lasts forever in this world?

                                           It’s the act of spreading negative thoughts and feelings over

                                           others. It has grown on to a length where those things are
                                           the ones which unite us. But let’s look into our life and think

                                           about where we faced this. For an average human with decent

                                           goals and lifestyle who thinks that they are raising their life in

                                           a correct way, there comes the toxic people ready to spread
                                           those unhealthy vibes on us.


                                           Where does this go? Where did it all start? Who to blame for
                                           all the toxicity in our mind? The act of toxicity exists just by a

                                           mere appearance  of  a  person. How,  you  ask? That’s what
          Vishwa @ Santhosh S
               2018 - 22, ECE              we call Body Shaming – the ultimate weapon of disrespect
                                           and humiliation by deriding a person’s physical appearance.

                                           A brief about this is that the Body shaming is the act of saying

                                           something negative about a person's body. It can be about

                                           your own body or someone else's. The commentary can be

                                           about a person's size, age, hair, clothes, food, hair, or level

          34    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[of perceived attractiveness. Although a lot of        adapt or perish to these ridicules are the only

             anti-bullying societies and communities have          ways to get out of this. Though I started to
             taken  it  as  their oath  to  spread  awareness      adapt to this hell hole. It became evident that

             about  the banes of the disaster, it doesn’t          I needed change. A change that is needed

             stop  and  even it  affects a  person’s  mental       not only for my mental health but also for

             health right from his/her childhood.                      my physical self. That’s the day  where I

             The best example comes from my life.  A               took those enough and much needed steps

             life which has been ridiculed day  in and             to tone my physique, attitude  and lifestyle.
             out during those school days just by measly           The undesirable one in the school is now the

             minutes of  my  appearance.  How?  Body               unignorable one with the goal to reach the

             Shaming. Why? Apparently, they wanted to              top despite the barriers.

             be dominant, feel that they are top and have          To those who are reading this and dejected
             fun with another equal’s expense. And the             about  whatever  negative feedback and life

             cost? Crying and mourning to the core and             hurdles you  receive,  never give up!   Don’t

             smashing my head to find a way to get out             lose your hope on those illogical comments

             of this mess. The more I faced this, the more         and start working on your dreams, passion
             I realized that mourning for this trifling waste      and lifestyle. The fruitful reward will be yours

             is not worth the time and mental health which         in the times to come. Remember, consistent

             I sacrificed.                                         hard work will never go unrewarded!

             Those ridicules never end and so should we.

             I felt that either a change in our lifestyle into

             something much more soothing to oneself or



































                                                                                       Expressions '22     35]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[A Look into The Book






                                                   "An hour spent reading is stolen from paradise"

                                                                                         -Thomas Wharton

                                           Humans are born  with an innate tendency to  learn, which

                                           continues from birth until the end. It  helps in gaining
                                           knowledge about various subjects. The more profound insight

                                           about anything comes from reading, and that makes us more

                                           confident. Reading  is beneficial  because it helps with your

                                           overall  development. Once  you start reading, it transports

                                           you to another world and helps you escape the stresses  of
                                           everyday life. When a person starts loving the habit of reading,
                Bhuvanikha S
                 2019 - 23, IT             believe me, they eventually get addicted to it. Reading helps in
                                           the development of your linguistic skills and vocabulary. It is
                                           beneficial to read a good book for a few minutes, which can

                                           improve the functioning of the brain and enhance memory

                                           power. Technology has prevailed and, inspite of the birth and

                                           widespread usage of e-books and audiobooks, the traditional


          36    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[method still remains invincible. Here I would         that led to any treasure, he continued to read

             like to share a short story which emphasizes          the books and ended up reading the entire
             the importance of reading.                            stack. Finally, he realized that “BOOKS” were

             Once there lived a son who was too reluctant          his  father’s property and “KNOWLEDGE”

             to gain knowledge. In contrast to his character,      was the profit he gained. Years later, his

             his father was a  great  scholar in the field         knowledge navigated his career and made it

             of literature. He was so worried about  the           a successful one.
             future  of  his only  unemployed  son. It  was        From being a useless person to a respected

             always a contentious situation, as the father         citizen,  we can strongly believe  that books

             always forced him to make some efforts for            have the ability to change one’s life. To be

             his upliftment. But all of a sudden, his father       honest, I'm not a bibliophile, but I desperately
             was bedridden. After some days of struggle,           want  to be one. There is a wide variety of

             his father passed away. The abandoned son             books like novels, Motivation etc., It need not

             was puzzled, as his father was the only ray           always  be  in English, it  can also be  books

             of hope. He didn’t know what he would do              of local languages. The ultimate gain from
             for his next meal. Fortunately, there came his        this wonderful habit is “knowledge”. For the

             father’s close friend, an advocate, who had           newbies out there, spend at least 30 minutes

             a piece of paper in his hand. The son asked           per  day.  As  quoted  by  Garrison  Keillor,

             the advocate  whether his father had  any             "A book is a gift you can open again and
             sort of wealth left for him. The advocate was         again”. So, presenting a book is the best

             quick enough to reply that his dad had left           thing anyone could ever receive. A fact worth

             nothing but a paper and handed it over to             mentioning  is  at our Literary Club of PTU,

             him. The piece of paper had 3 words written           books are given as a token of appreciation,
             in it, “READ THE BOOK”.                               which can indulge many minds into the habit


             The son got excited as he assumed that his            of reading. I hope I will  become a good
             dad  had  left some treasure or  something.           reader and so will you. Always remember,

             He immediately raided his dad’s bookshelf.                  “A room without books is like

             There were hundreds of books. He razed the                      a body without a soul”
             shelf  and found nothing. He  even  thought                                                 -Cicero.

             of  selling them,  but  thought  that  he would

             get little profit out of it. Thinking for a while,

             he came to the conclusion that there might

             be a clue inside the book, and he started to
             read one. As a result of not finding any hint



                                                                                       Expressions '22     37]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[Depp vs. Heard and the Incessant



        Stream of Opinions




                                           I was eating breakfast and watching the news, and I found out

                                           that Johnny Depp was suing Amber Heard for defamation. I

                                           caught this story in the middle, and I was curious to know more,
                                           not that I particularly  cared about  Johnny  Depp or Amber

                                           Heard but I was just really curious. So, I looked up some news

                                           articles from the New York Times and the New Yorker and I

                                           was now up to speed. I did not know at this moment that I was

                                           about to get caught in a whirlwind discussion with my fellow
                                           brothers on the internet about the private lives of two people.

                                           I was bombarded on all social media platforms, and I went

                    Heena S                through all the phases of getting hooked to a story.
                2019 - 23, ECE
                                           Number one is lying to myself and telling myself that I don't

                                           care and scrolling past every mention of this trial

                                           Number two is slowly scrolling past these mentions, and the

                                           speed of my scrolling these mentions lower every day.

                                           Number three is accepting that I am one of the lowly crowds,
                                           interested in the details of a marriage falling to pieces,


          38    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[Depp vs Heard is only one the many things
                                                                  the internet has presented to me this week. I

                                                                  am treated with much more serious news like

                                                                  climate  change and the eventual doom of

                                                                  the world. The incessant stream of opinions
                                                                  of  other  people  and  my  own  about  these

                                                                  varied things have completely occupied my

                                                                  headspace. I go about life normally, but I feel

                                                                  my mood change completely after a whiff of
                                                                  the internet.

                                                                  And I'm not alone.


                                                                  In an article titled “The science  behind

            especially  a celebrity  couple who is  airing        doomscrolling” by ABC news states,

            out their  dirty laundry for the world to see,        “Studies have linked poor  mental health to
            and they're doing so voluntarily might I add,         news exposure during negative and traumatic

            which just makes me feel like what I'm doing          events such as terrorist attacks  or  natural

            isn't such a bad thing after all.                     disasters; the more news a person consumes

            A ritual part of the third phase is discovering       during and after these events, the more likely

            the comments section. Lady Gaga once said             they are to suffer from depression, stress and
            that social media is the toilet of the internet       anxiety.”

            and I am here to tell you that the comments           All the news we receive is never good, and it

            section is the toilet of social media. Here           especially seems so, ever since the pandemic.

            is where I  discover that  there are  people          And I don't know what to care about, since

            much more invested in this trial than I am. It        there are so many pressing issues and other
            surprised me because when you read these              less important issues on which I am tempted

            comments, the amount of care people has for           give my take.

            the troubles of rich people is baffling. But I'm      So, what is  the solution to doomscrolling?
            no better.                                            I have decided to  allow myself only two


            I'm not here to tell you that people only care        opinions per day. This way I will pick my
            about  celebrities and  aren't talking about          battles. So, I have decided to let go of my

            any serious  issues.  Because the one thing           thoughts on the 50-million-dollar defamation

            the internet is never  short of are opinions.         suit now. Wish me luck!

            Opinions on anything and  everything you
            can dream of. And that is what troubles me.


                                                                                       Expressions '22     39]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[Borders





                                           Hi! To all the readers, I’m earth. I’m about a billion years old

                                           and I’ve seen enough in this life span. I’ve seen you all evolve
                                           "
                                            from a cell to a full-fledged organism. I’ve seen a lot but you

                                            know the funniest of all are ‘humans’. They have lived just for

                                            a few centuries and first thing they did was barging fences
                                            into me and dividing me into 195 different parts. And this

                                            isn’t the funniest part, they actually fight over the lines they

                                            made. Millions have been buried over these random lines.

                                            They didn’t choose  where to be born, they didn’t choose

                                            where to live but they still chose, restriction over their own
                 Nikhil Sharma              freedom. I never stopped anyone from exploring any part of
            2019 - 23, Mechanical
                                            the globe but they have restricted themselves.

                                             As I see, they are all my children but I’ve heard they introduce

                                            themselves  with some different identities. Some of them

                                            are Indians, some of them are Americans… aren’t they all

                                            humans?


          40    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[HUMANS, as they call themself-the  most               this race and introduced ‘UNITED NATIONS’

             advanced species. What kind of advancement            as a common flag for all. I thought that was

             is it, that teaches them to drift apart? Rather       the first step of them going back to humanity

             than  growing  together,  they  are  being            but it too didn’t work out as it was supposed

             destructive to themselves.  I account 510.1           to. We still saw wars and borders. Although,
             million km2 of area for about 8 billion people        not everyone is out of their mind, a group of

             which approximately gives 64 m2 per person,           few people who shared their borders, came

             which I believe is good enough for a person           together to act smart and formed a union
             to live. But still out of no common sense, this       among themselves, called ‘THE EUROPEAN

             ‘most advanced species’, made borders and             UNION’.  These people stand  under the

             divided me in such an unjustifiable manner            same flag, belong to the same race and act

             that they need to fight even for their survival       like what they are ‘THE MOST ADVANCED

             sometimes.                                            SPECIES’.  "

             For past century I saw an era of colonisation,
             which  in turn took a million  lives,  led to a       This is what mother earth had to say about us

             thousand wars and even two world wars. And            but there are a few opinions I’d like to share

             above everything, nuclear  explosions.  This          as well; I too have lived a life over 20 years

             would be the only species trying to destroy           and  I’ve lived experiences  of  a  war  going
             their own kind.                                       on for past 75 days and public genocides.


             Who introduced these borders to them?                 I aspire to become an army officer but not
             I didn’t;  sea has no lines-water flows as it         to fight over some imaginary lines, I want to

             wants; wind doesn’t stop according to their           become a warrior for our own self, fighting

             fences; sun falls as per wish; trees grow as          against the negative elements of the society
             they want. Then why have they introduced              and  not  fighting  against  a  loyal  and  very

             borders, for their children can’t grow freely.        skilled officer who was born a few kilometres

             India,  where you  belong to,  has a  history         away.  I  choose not  to  obey  the restrictions

             going back in the scripts that says that they         someone else has put on me, I want to travel

             untied the whole earth at a period of time            different parts of the world by my own will;

             but now be it 1947, 1965, 1971, 1999 or               I want to see the beauty of Islamabad, the
             be it 2022; they have also been involved in           arts of Beijing, architecture of Barcelona and

             just protecting what’s their own and not into         every part that fascinates me.

             uniting everyone.

             In 1945, after the massive destruction. Few           ‘I AM HUMAN AT FIRST, HUMANITY IS MY

             people came together as the smarter ones of           RELIGION AND IT DEFINES WHO I AM’


                                                                                       Expressions '22     41]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[The Spiral or a Circle




                                                             crashed into the wall. Well, I removed my

                                                             VR headset, on the screen “45% progressed

                                                             to cure Thalassophobia (intense  fear of

                                                             large  water  bodies),  Congratulations".  The
                                                             emergency alarm turned off again! I should

                                                             contact the manufacturer if it occurs again.

                                                             Readers, assume that technology exists.
                          Arulmeni G
                  2020 - 24, Mechatronics                    Coming back, it's not a kind of test, it's about

                                                             you and me. We regret missed opportunities,
            It  is the seventh day  against the ocean.  but fail to realise there are advantages in the

            Toasting  under the sun, a  drenched raft  missing. The reality is we are running out of

            anytime up for betrayal, empty food cans  coal, quickly grab  the adapter  and  charge

            and a storage box. Should I throw it away,  to the fullest. On an average students spend

            or will it rescue me from this saline monster?  10 hrs on screen covering a lifestyle within
            The place is calm and yet I am broken and  a comfort zone of fixed radius. Stay focused

            ambiguous.  With strength from nowhere,  and  move on. Irrespective of your  choices,

            I cleared my raft and lied down under the  leave room for your passion.
            sun. I didn’t notice the flare inside the box,   If you feel exhausted, take a break for a while

            that  now  starts disappearing  in the dark,     and attempt again.

            below  the ocean. In  this critical situation,

            I managed to get fishes  with my clothes,
            increasing  my survival  rate. Few minutes

            later,  I  heard  a  motor  sound  which was  a

            melody for my ears. I didn’t have the energy

            to yell and they didn’t detect me as they were
            kilometres away. There must be land where

            they came from. So, I waited for hours.

            Finally I saw an island. Heart pounding with

            excitement and the raft about to sink, I must
            retreat the flare, otherwise death.  Without

            any  hesitation, I  dived into  the water  and



          42    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[Draupadi - A Feminist View























                            Nappinnai V
                           2020 - 24, ECE



               This article is written with the purpose to        women uncomfortable and the massacre
               bring out the difference between how male          that takes place after, shows how valueless

               and female writers vary with respect to            dalit lives are considered to be. We cannot

               expression of their female character.While         expect justice as the scales are always in

               Mahabaratha deals with a Draupadi who              favour of people in positions of power but

               felt helpless  on being stripped  off her          our body is ours alone.Even when she is
               clothes with nobody but the incarnation of         stripped naked and assaulted her only

               God to come to her rescue while men in the         response being, "You can strip me, but

               court don't object.Even though this was one        how can you clothe me again?"   is a
               of the reasons for Kurukshetra war it was          point to be appreciated. Mahasweta Devi's

               depicted as nothing more but a mere ego            Dopdi is  the woman everyone needs  to

               clash  between men.  While  Mahaswetha             normalize. The one who is a brave leader,

               Devi's Draupadi is a revolutionary.The plot        doesn't  need a  man to  save her, driven

               starts with a woman on the run after her           by  a  purpose,  who  isn't confined by  the
               husband is killed in a police encounter.As         constraints of patriarchy, isn't ashamed or

               the story progresses we come to know that          broken when they expect her to be.

               this is because they had killed a  person          Mahaswetha Devi  was one of a kind
               who deprived tribals of even basic needs           and a pioneer  who devoted her  life

               like  water. There  is  also a line  in  which     in empowerment of  tribes and  also

               Dopdi mentions sexual objectification.             highlighting importance of feminism.

               This shows how men holding higher ranks

               in society think they have the right to make



                                                                                       Expressions '22     43]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[A New Kid in Town


                                                              messaged one of the group admins, about

                                                              what’s going on there. He then explained to

                                                              me everything about rules and regulations,
                                                              how to frame a sentence etc. I wrote my first

                                                              sentence  there,  it was a Nanotale I think.

                                                              And well, see whose name was selected as

                                                              the top pick of the day.


                            Rishi S                             I was completely  amazed, and I didn’t
                   2020 - 24, Chemical                        know it’s gonna bring me to a point where

                                                              I write an article about it one day. So, my

        Gosh, that was tough. I didn’t even think I’ll        confidence was boosted, and I participated

        make it through, but here I am, with my first         in the daily events without fail. Everyone was

        ever article.  At first, I didn't have the slightest   eagerly participating in  the daily events,

        idea that a club that’s engaging people to            until that day. A poster of Curioso 2021 was
        develop soft skills  exists in my college (Or         put up in the group. I went through it, and I

        should I say, ‘University’). Well can’t blame         didn’t think many people would participate

        anyone, as we were amidst the pandemic.               in  that. Because,  in  online  classes  nobody

        Online classes  were going  on and  it was            answers  the staff’s call  if he/she  raises  a
        like everyday was going without me doing              question.  And  to  my surprise, there were

        almost nothing productive. And then I                 plenty  of  them,  and  it  was  the first time I

        received a call from my friend. He said, “Do          met with amazing people, with amazing

        you know that our college has a club called           communication  skills  like  TC Adityaa,
        literary club?”. I was like, “What’s this mad         Michael Robin, Shree Vyshnavi……and the

        lad talking about?”.                                  list goes on.

          I requested him  to elaborate, and God! It            We were having a  positive rivalry in the

        took like an hour for him to explain it to me.        competitions, and everyone was giving

        I still wasn’t sure about what he was talking         their best to dethrone the Imaginary Lords

        about, but I thought I’ll give it a shot. So,         of “The literary Club of PTU”, that is the
        I joined the club’s WhatsApp group  and               department of ECE first years,  from the

        there were other guys with their completely           top  spot.  Since only three or  maybe  four

        jargonized sentences  which made  me                  students participated  from Chemical first
        hold back. As I was new there, I privately            year, we couldn’t take the position. But the



          44    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[competitive spirit was still pumping through.        were introduced to us and they took the

             For a few days, the group was silent since           place of their predecessors. It was a bitter

             the Mentors, who were basically from the             experience, for some days. It took a while

             final  years were  about  to graduate,  were         for me to get along with the new mentors.

             busy with placement and stuff. So, we held           But soon enough, the daily events  started
             back that will of fire of ours, for some time.       firing up, and the members were showing



























































             And the day came, where the Mentors had              their full-fledged participation.  Everybody

             to say their goodbyes. It was a really great         tried  their best,  including me, and  the
             experience having Swami Anna, Shafreena              results were shocking. I was selected as the

             Akka, Aishwarya Akka and Vicky Anna and              monthly winner. For a moment, I couldn’t

             others. Thanks for sparing your golden time          believe it myself. I was filled with happiness
             with us.                                             in my heart, and there were no words to


               A new day was born, and the new Mentors            explain it. And so, the events continued.



                                                                                       Expressions '22     45]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[It was the month of October 2021, when               and gradually people started to show interest
        the situation  healed up, and  the college            in participation.

        management finally  decided  to reopen                   A week passed by and we were behind

        the college  for students. We entered the             ECE by a massive 300 points. But that didn’t
        college as second years, it was a brand-new           stop us from participating. At the end of

        experience. For some times the participation          the week, to our surprise, we surpassed the

        was as usual and since then the participation         Department of ECE by 139 points, where we

        was drastically reduced, since all others were        were standing at 1069 points and they were

        getting busy with their subject stuff. But there      at 930. Now that the tables have turned, the
        was still participation. And it was the month         view of all the departments about Chemical

        of April when the posters of Curioso 2022             department change, the ECE guys accepted

        were put up in the group. I felt nostalgic, but       us as a true rival  and our positive  rivalry
        hadn't the slightest idea on how they would           continued till the final minute of the prelims

        conduct the events.  I hadn’t even  read the          of  the events, where every  one of  us were

        entire poster before I  went into the world           giving  our last resort attempt to boost our

        of imagination. Once I snapped back from              points even by a sliver amount of points. The
        imagination, it stated  that events  will be          three weeks, one hell of an experience. I was

        conducted in the chemical seminar hall. So,           overjoyed and so were my mates from my

        I gathered all my confidence.                         department.  As the final week is going  to

          Me  and  Devipriya,  one of  my  classmates,        begin next week, I’m expecting this positive

        went into the seminar hall, and it was the first      rivalry to continue and I hope that everyone

        time we were seeing the mentors in person.            would  have gained  at  least some useful
        They were so good,  and we participated               attributes from this event. I guess this article

        in a few events. We were the first ones to            will be coming up once all the events end.

        participate in the events it seemed. And after        So, for those who are reading it, don’t hold
        doing a few events we left for class. The next        back on what you’re aiming for. You may not

        day, the points table came up and we were             realize that  the path  to  success  sometimes

        in the second position, next to our untouched         requires very little effort than you think.

        rivals the Second year ECE department. The

        mentors told, that the chemical department
        hasn't even been in the top  five for years,

        and this was the first time. Too inspired by

        that word, me and others tried to improve
        the participation of the chemical department,



          46    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[Antidote to Suicide



                                                                through. People who are feeling as horrible
                         Trigger
                         Trigger                                as you are right now. So, get assistance right

                                                                now. You can make it. There are things you
                        Warning                                 may do to alleviate your agony and decrease
                        Warning

                                                                your urge to terminate your life.

                                                                 There is no one reason why someone

                                                                may consider  suicide.  Suicide  makes  no

                                                                distinctions  based on age, gender, money,
                                                                colour,  religious preference, or  sexual

                                                                orientation. Suicidal ideation  may be

                                                                accompanied by signs of a mental disease

                                                                or several life circumstances. It might be the

                                                                death of a loved one, financial difficulties,
                      Shreyasi Majumder
                         2020 - 24, ECE                         relationship  problems, job loss,  health
                                                                concerns, or any big life transition.
           There is no shame in receiving  treatment
                                                                 Common warning signs that someone may
           for mental health issues. We frequently hear
                                                                be thinking about suicide include- changes
           reminders to  "be  strong,"  but  it  is critical
                                                                in  mood, giving  away prized  possessions,
           to be honest with ourselves  when  we or
                                                                putting  final  affairs in order,  withdrawing,
           the individuals we care about are thinking
                                                                changes in physical appearance, prior
           negatively. Taking care of oneself by seeking
                                                                suicide attempts, alcohol or drug use, high-
           medical attention is a  top  concern. If  it
                                                                risk  behaviours, making statements with
           feels  significant, it probably  is. Recognize
                                                                themes of hopelessness, helplessness,  and
           that suicide  ideas are serious  and require
                                                                fear of becoming a burden, making verbal
           your  attention,  whether you  are listening
                                                                suicide threats, such as “I want to die” or “I’m
           to someone else or dealing with your own
                                                                going to kill  myself”, any other significant
           concerns.
                                                                changes.
            Suicidal feelings  indicate  that  you  are
                                                                 As we all may have heard, May is Mental
           experiencing  more suffering  than you can
                                                                Health Month. Throughout May, individuals
           bear at the time. But keep in mind that no
                                                                and organisations are encouraged to learn
           crisis lasts forever. You can feel better and
                                                                more about mental health and how to care
           stay safe with assistance. People make it

                                                                                       Expressions '22     47]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[for it. I want to pen some concrete ways to           and respect.  Surround yourself with positive
        improve one’s emotional health- one should            people. The people around us affect our

        deal oneself with kindness. It's easy to say,         mental health. If you're feeling  down,  ask

        but it's very important for mental health. We         yourself with whom you're spending. Are the











































































        know that it's easy to get your loved ones up         people  you  spend your  time positive? Do

        and it's not so easy to get yourself up, but we       they bring you joy? Are they encouraging? It
        encourage you to treat them with kindness             is important to pay attention to all of these.




          48    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[Exercise contributes significantly to our mental  romantic dark comedy released on 22 June
             health. Find the kind of physical activity you are  2012,  where the main motto  was  creating

             enjoying and stick to it! There are numerous  antidote  to  suicide among  individuals

             benefits to exercising. Healthy eating habits.  suffering from this. The film is an in-depth

             Studies show the benefits of a healthy diet.  look at the psychological dilemma regarding
             That doesn't mean  you can't and shouldn't  the primordial existence of life. He reiterates

             treat yourself occasionally. Just look at what  that you can "shock someone by letting them

             you eat, as it makes a difference.  Get enough  know that death is imminent and inevitable." It

             sleep at night. Sleep is very important to our  is a black comedy that successfully evokes the
             overall well-being. Whether you understand it  perception of life. Comic elements are cleverly

             or not, the amount of sleep you get can make  used to highlight the fear of death.

             a big difference  in how you feel  and your         The subject  of the film  'Hemlock  Society'

             overall emotional well-being. Say no. This can    seems different, which explores the lives  of
             be difficult for many. Don't be afraid to say no   people who want to commit suicide. Actually

             to the situation. If you need time alone, say no   'Hemlock Society' is an organisation  that

             to the invited plan. You must do what is most     helps people with information on supporting

             useful to you.                                    legislation   permitting    physician-assisted-

               Know  which  stress management  strategy  is  suicide.
             best for you. Knowing which coping strategy        Sometimes, it may not be possible to create

             works best for you is important in life. There    an awareness  suddenly inside  someone

             are many stress management strategies you         just by applying some  speech  or awareness

             can implement, but you need to find the one       program.     Human      mind    always    finds

             that works best for you.  In a life that gives    something  new and interesting, from which
             you mercy, it is very easy for us to give grace   at least the human can find some interest to

             to others, but it is not so easy to give grace    understand it. Same concept if we can apply

             to  ourselves. Never forget  that  we  are all    for preventing suicide- like making movie,
             human. In other words, you make a mistake.        animation, web shows on it, obviously where

             It's okay if you make a mistake. Give yourself    people will find their interest in life as well as

             grace and do your best to learn from those        will find suicide as a useless thing, precisely,

             mistakes. Don't be afraid to ask for help. There   which can make people feel their life as a gift.

             are resources and help available. Call the        So, let’s try together to save lives,  to create
             National Suicide Prevention Lifeline at 1 800     Antidote to Suicide.

             273 8255 to talk to a trained crisis counsellor.

              Hemlock Society is an Indian Bengali



                                                                                       Expressions '22     49]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[The Life of an NCC Cadet





                                                              personality and mainly acquires leadership
                                                              qualities.


                                                              During the three years of  your  training
                                                              program,  you  start  your  first year  as  a

                                                              fresher  and  you'll be given a basic rank.

                                                              Every weekend you will be having Unit
                                                              parades and classes involving both technical
                         R C Yajour
                      Kichenamourty                           and common subjects in NCC. Yes, we
                 2020 - 24, Mechatronics                      do have  theory classes  and camps. As I


          Being an NCC cadet, you get to experience           have already mentioned, it's not just about

          and explore all the important aspects one           physical activities and drills, it's also about
          can get during their life. Be it trekking,          character development and enhancing your

          mountaineering, paragliding, parasailing,           knowledge in fields like general knowledge,

          scuba diving, kayaking, safari, etc. Oh! The        current affairs, aerodynamics and principles

          list goes on. By the way, what's NCC ?              of Flight (Air wing), Map  Reading and

          The National Cadet  Corps (NCC) is a                Weapon Training(Army Wing), Seamanship
          voluntary movement and the Indian Military          and  Naval warfare  &  Navigation  (Naval

          cadet corps of the Indian Armed Forces. The         Wing).

          training program is for 3 years for college         Apart from this, we have activities like firing

          students like us. We get the Basic Military         (.22 rifle, SLR, INSAS), Flying Aircraft (co-

          Training and also experience what it is to be       piloting), scuba diving, swimming, boat
          in the Indian Armed Forces.                         pulling,  mountaineering,  trekking,  para

          Being  a NCC cadet, you are of course               courses, cultural events, tent pitching, group

          unique and different from the rest of your          discussions, extempores, public awareness

          college mates. To be in NCC is being                campaigns, etc.

          unique, dedicated,hard working, punctual,           In NCC, You can join any one  of the three
          disciplined  and most importantly learning          wings - The Army, The Navy and The Air

          what is life as it shows what is to be an officer   Force. Unlike most of the Military Institutions,

          in the Indian Armed Forces.  It inculcates          young girls can also join NCC. There are
          the attitude of never giving up, builds self-       various different camps like Combined

          esteem and self confidence, develops your           Annual Training  Camp (CATC), Republic


          50    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[Day Camp(RDC), Leadership Camps, Youth                in NCC were incredible and undescribable.

             Exchange Programme  (YEP),  etc. The most             Although  my first year has passed during

             significant one is the RDC camp, New Delhi            curfew, my second year journey was really

             where your performance will be in front of the        a  life changing experience. I  have already

             President of India, Prime Minister of India and       attended a couple of camps and one among
             leading officers in the Indian Armed Forces .         them is a National Camp. You get to know and

             You'll be able to interact with officers as high      learn about  cultural diversity and National

             as  Lieutenant  General and  equivalent. The          Integration through these camps. I have co-
             YEP connects cadets from across the Nations           piloted a Microlite Aircraft and have already

             promoting integrity and sense of unity. The           completed two sorties  of my flight. Yes! I

             one extraordinary thing about  NCC is  that           have seen   our beautiful town Puducherry

             you  can achieve  and do  things that  your           from the cockpit of an aircraft! I have fired a

             fellow college mates can't even imagine.              .22 Rifle and a DBBL Rifle. These are among

             Well,  now coming  to the main  part of this          the  lifetime achievements according to me
             article, NCC Puducherry Group Headquarters            only possible through NCC and that too for

             is located at Lawspet near Puducherry Airport.        free of cost!!! I have participated  in public

             Joining NCC is still a dream for many students        awareness campaigns, coastal cleaning

             of our age in our country. But are not able           activities,  blood   donation     campaigns,
             to do so mainly due to the inaccessibility of         COVID relief  duties,Traffic Duties and also

             NCC units. We never know the importance of            beach parades during Independence Day,

             something until and unless it is gone from us.        Puducherry Liberation Day, Republic Day

             Being in such close proximity to all of us but        representing my Unit..
             still as of now the total students representing       From my experiences, I have understood that

             our college is down to just 5 cadets and that         in  order to prosper participating in  varied

             too in the Air wing only. The main reason is          activities  and taking up responsibilities  are

             the lack of awareness. We are Engineering             very important. Trust me, it is worth the shot!
             students and  there's a  ton  of  opportunities

             available to us in the Indian Armed Forces

             also apart from the ones offered by our TNP

             cell. NCC provides a perfect platform for us
             in achieving this career.

             I am a Flight Cadet in 1(Puducherry) Air

             Squadron Fly NCC. I am currently  in my

             third year of my NCC life and my two years



                                                                                       Expressions '22     51]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[The Dictionary





                                           The actual book sits in front of me as I venture on to write

                                           about  it. One of the most common books yet underrated,
                                           the dictionary has always had enough recognition from me.

                                           Thick; that word would be a good one to start with. The size of

                                           it is enough to scare off anyone who for once actually wants
                                           to approach it. And the extremely small sized text intimidates

                                           one who had mustered the courage to pick it up.

                                             The blue hard covered book sits in front of me: the edges

                                           are excessively tattered; however the wisdom-filled pages are

                                           intact. One advantage of having a dictionary at hand, which
               Joseph Beniel J             is also practically the only use for it except when you’re really
          2021 - 25, Mechatronics
                                           sleepy but haven’t a pillow near, is that you can refer to the

                                           meanings of the words your mind nudges at you or the ones

                                           from your eyes. Given the extreme value of this particular

                                           book, in the current scenario it is one of the least considered
                                           books. Yes, we do go to it when we want to know the meaning



          52    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[of a word  so badly, but  what about  other           to the dictionary every time we see the devil

             times? Like when we could have just known             of literature staring mockingly at us?

             the meaning of a four letter word that would          All this is not for the plea of my dictionary to
             have spared us from literary extinction. I tell       pick it up; it is so that we don’t miss out on

             you that this intimidating book that you have         the fireworks of the literary sky.

             never  read fully before is more a treasure

             trove than the dungeon we have all thought

             it was.

             So how could we squeeze the most out of this
             vocabulary mammoth? Consider it as your

             friend: just because we don’t need our friend

             at all times doesn’t mean we don’t go up to

             him and say a momentary hi in the least next
             time we are perfectly fine (Which is less likely).

             Perseverance is the key to success. Everybody

             has read a book or story or at least heard

             one in his lifetime, but how many of us turn


                                                                                       Expressions '22     53]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[My Mom's Pep-talk





                                           Welcome to the overthinkers club guys! Here let me list out

                                           a few things you probably would be feeling as a newbie into

                                           college life. And let me guide you through that with my not-

                                           so-good overthinking skills so you can ignore the overthinking
                                           part because I’ve already done it for you.


                                           A feeling of inferiority

                                           So, my friend, you keep seeing around you a lot of people
                                           who think of themselves as cool. It's because they come on

                                           super bikes and hang out most of the time, probably bunking

                                           classes too. Let me get straight, they are not cool. They are just
                   Kailash. S
                2021 - 25, ECE             attention seekers. Trust me you do not need it.

                                           You don’t have to fit in a group

                                           Actually, you don’t need a circle  of friends.  It is  better or

                                           more than enough to have a good friend whom you can trust
                                           because I’m sure you don’t need an Amber Heard if you’re

                                           Johnny Depp.

          54    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[You wish you were as influential as others            further movement will lead to the loss of self-

             are                                                   respect. It doesn't matter how much you like

             What are you even going to do with those              someone. To build something real, you need

             influences? Why do you even want it? Don’t            to  be yourself — and if you’re not,  it can
             focus on acquiring it. What you must focus on         backfire.

             acquiring is respect. Actually, you don’t even        Is it okay for me to be a loner?

             have to acquire it. Just focus on yourself and        Everyone may have a facet that may not be

             be considerate towards  others. Eventually,           socially acceptable.  Everyone wants  to  be
             you will earn it. With respect comes influence        loved and appreciated. People may not show

             too. Two birds with a stone!                          it but even the most popular one in the class

             You  wish  you  were  liked  by  everyone             would have feelings of loneliness. It may be

             around you                                            a passing phase where one feels distant from

             Even after you put in a considerable amount           and misunderstood by others. It may also be

             of effort to gain others' attention,  you do          due  to  a  lack of  belongingness. Embrace

             not get the expected results. Stop there! Any         who you are and things will fall in place.




                                                                                       Expressions '22     55]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[After Lockdown Experience




                                                           would  be having offline classes.  I couldn’t

                                                           explain my enthusiasm  and curiosity. Having

                                                           heard a lot about the University campus and

                                                           stories about  university  life,  I was excited to

                                                           start mine. On the reopening day, entering the
                                                           campus felt like living my dreams, to see the

                                                           cartooned and captioned DPs in person. To

                                                           bump into each other and talk like long time
                       Keerthana A P
                       2021 - 25, Civil                    friends was an out of the world feeling.

                                                           I’ve never seen such a large campus and to
        Having  spent almost 2 years  in  lockdown,
                                                           roam around with friends from various states
        being cooped up inside the same house, with
                                                           made me realize all the stories I heard from my
        the fear of being affected by covid, many
                                                           seniors were true. It has been only 4 months
        students have experienced  frustration getting
                                                           now and I’m loving it to the fullest and I hope
        on their veins. I, like all my friends, spent my
                                                           I feel the same for the next three and a half
        whole 12th  standard  in lockdown. I  started
                                                           years.
        longing to step out of the house and see my

        friends. Earlier, I used to long for holidays, to
        stay at home and enjoy. The pandemic made

        me realize that just staying at home could lead

        to various health issues and mental stress.

        At last, the good  news came in that  I have

        got  admission in Puducherry  Technological

        University.  With that  excitement, came the
        damper  that  we would  be  having online

        classes. Trying to soak in the disappointment,

        we turned to online mode once more. I became
        acquainted  with my classmates  and  college

        mates through online chatting.

        Three months went  by,  online classes were

        going  on and  then it was declared that  we




          56    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[Time

























                       Ludfin Morais
                 2021 - 25, Mechatronics


             Enjoy each and every moment of life

             because, once lost, time can never be

             regained. At the same time, fulfill your

             responsibilities  instead of running
             away  from them. Past has passed.

             So, stop worrying about it. Learn from

             your mistakes and try to be a better

             version of yourself.








































                                                                                       Expressions '22     57]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[Teenage Desires





                                           Every person experiences a bunch of emotions at different

                                           stages of life. It's an eyes wide shut fact that teenagers develop

                                           subtle fantasies involving people of the opposite sex. These

                                           are the instances  where the mind experiences  fluctuations
                                           in thoughts. Sometimes, we lose control over our emotions.

                                           I  am sure that  every single person reading this must have

                                           undergone teenage attraction. Sometimes this attraction that

                                           wears a mask of superficial love ruins the beautiful careers
                                           of many youngsters. Teenage love can be an infatuation as

                                           a result of active  hormones.  According  to reports, mental

                                           development in teens is truncated due to these overpowering

                                           emotions. Teens quite often lack social skills, morals, thinking
                                           ability and judgment.

                   Sahiti M                The feeling of the first crush sometimes unsettles once prudence
          2021 - 25, Mechanical
                                           . We can't decide  the qualities of a person just by external

                                           looks. I would say that the mind is mature when it gains the

                                           potential to see the beauty of souls. We must be dedicated

                                           and passionate about our aims, especially during our teenage
                                           years.

                                           Unfortunately, due to various  influences,  students focus  on

                                           relationships rather than academics. So it is highly important

                                           for teenagers to set goals and stay focused.

                                            "If you don't rule your mind it rules you"



          58    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="59"><![CDATA[P
                                                  oems























































































                                                                                       Expressions '22     59]]></page><page Index="60"><![CDATA[Dreams


























                                                  Harish Balaji
                                                  2012 - 16, IT
                                               Amazon, Quebec



                        Dreams… with all the glory, perfection and the sights set to ascend,

                        Maybe merely mirages, moving targets, or just a means to an end?
                            From King’s improvisation “I have a dream”, Till Dr. Kalam

                          Said they transform into thoughts and then action, did I dream
                             Of Dreams so dreamy, I dwell in them for epochs on end.




                               Grass be greener, victory sweeter and sunsets prettier,
                              In the colorful kaleidoscope that the mind may render.

                              Glorification, albeit unwarranted, paints a thorny path,

                            As a bed of roses, unnoticed pains yearn for an audience.
                              After all, it may rosy be, a tool for transforming reality,

                           But whence do they say, one might wonder, albeit unseeming

                           It’s not what it was to be, ones you look up to, at their zenith.



                        A dutiful student works harder, a talented girl pleads passionately,
                       To break free from the shackles from birth - gender, race or religion,

                      A parent who spends miserly on self, he saves up for a carefree child,

                             A fervent lover strives to salvage an abusive relationship,
                         Her children tolerate and hope she’s right, later hope she leaves,

                         A social service worker trying to help them, and others in trouble,
                      Tries to find a solution, tip the scales for the better, make a difference;



          60    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="61"><![CDATA[A skillful worker exhibits unwavering work ethic, post a promotion snub,

                         A young couple, against invisible societal barriers, yearn for each other,

                        Fighting the system, a journalist, a lawyer or an honest politician struggles,
                                       When backed by Dreams in different forms –
                                              catalyst, elixir, or so much more.




                             I dwell in Dreams still, of the possibility of happiness and peace,
                             Nobler outcomes still, equality, and freedom to say one’s piece,

                         Of harmless levity at adversity, selflessness and much-needed humanity,

                        Of development, upliftment and reprieve from unfathomable melancholy,
                               Much to the grandiose proportions of the visionaries before,

                              Since such an abode heralds hope, irrespective of the dwellers.
































































                                                                                       Expressions '22     61]]></page><page Index="62"><![CDATA[Love and Music





                                                           To see my crush and then

                                                           Kept my eyes on her rosy cheeks

                                                           Looking at her, I lost myself

                                                           Fluttering of her eyes

                                                           Made my ears deaf




                                                           Those humming birds on the tree near the
                                                           window
                    Moncher Lucien D
                       2018 - 22, EIE                      Grasped my attention.

        Cool breeze across my face,                        Then,

        That touched the warmth of my cheeks,              I found myself

        Lying back on the chair,                           Felt the sweet sound of symphony

        With a pen and a notebook on the table.            And so, I wished to sing a duet in harmony
                                                           And that too, with her.


        Heard the flutter of the turning pages
        That provoked me to scribble down                  As she comforts me in my solitude

        But my eyes pleaded me                             Hoping for her to look at me.

        To stay calm and to relax

                                                           Time slipped...

        Oh my god…                                         Slowly, she turned towards me.
                                                           It filled me with awe.


        Obscure thoughts on my head,                       Joy and happiness blossomed within me,

        Lady with the chalk and that damned book,          I heard the first note of melody,

        Standing in front of me,                           Felt our hearts click in serenity,
        Her blabbering  mouth  with  a  monotonous         Noted my hands tapping away,

        tone,                                              And soon I knew, we would sing our song.

        Made me to look at her weirdly

                                                           Make the perfect composition,

        Looking for a long-lasting symphony                For a masterpiece worth a life-time.
        Just turned, to my right side



          62    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="63"><![CDATA[Risk


























                                                      Sreemathy S
                                                     2018 - 22, ECE


                                            To laugh is to risk appearing a fool,

                                         To weep is to risk appearing sentimental,

                                       To reach out to another is to risk involvement,

                                    To expose feelings is to risk exposing your true self,

                            To place your ideas and dreams before a crowd is to risk their loss,

                                                 To hope is to risk despair,

                                                   To try is to risk failure.


                       But risks must be taken because the greatest hazard in life is to risk nothing.

                           The person who risks nothing does nothing, has nothing, is nothing.

                                            He may avoid suffering and sorrow,

                                      But he cannot learn, feel, change, grow or live.

                           Chained by his servitude he is a slave who has forfeited all freedom.

                                              Only a person who risks is free.






















                                                                                       Expressions '22     63]]></page><page Index="64"><![CDATA[The Mechanics of Life


























                                                    Sriram B
                                           2018 - 22, Mechanical

                                                Hello Expressions!

                                  Poetry should be more expression than forms


                                    For rhythm is more important than rhyme...

                                           Let me alter all these norms,

                                  And give me a go ahead for “One last time”!




                             How I slopped off from the 1st year would be a mystery,

                            For a few know the credits all go to Maths and Chemistry.

                              Into the second year and it seemed “I’m in for a treat”

                              But the first hour mechanics class screamed “Retreat”.





                                      Thanks to the “WE ARE SPARTA” spirit,

                                      I cleared my third semester with merit.

                            Days passed, thinking of vectors and tensors in the bus...

                                    But this corona guy came out of syllabus!




                                The fingers which were engrossed in taking notes,

                                 Were now reluctant to unmute the headphones.





          64    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="65"><![CDATA[With no one to pep up and say “Run forrest, run”

                                             I knew a solitary battle has begun.





                                        Wave after wave of pandemic lockdowns...

                                      It was obvious this thing was getting me down.

                                        Lockdowns lifted and the college summoned

                                        Kick-starting my bike with a spirit of Demon.




                                           We knew we had only a few days left,

                                    And thus lived out our final year days at its behest..


                                     Life has shown that success rates are one in tenth,

                                  But my college has edified me to take it on with strength

                                         Consider this as an ode to my college life

                                    And thanks for hearing me out for “One last Time”






















































                                                                                       Expressions '22     65]]></page><page Index="66"><![CDATA[Depression


























                                            Umar Hussain Wani
                                                2018 - 22, Civil

                                          Hello, my name is depression

                                                    I live in everyone

                                              I have no gender or religion

                                                my age is your maturity...



                                            your overthinking gives me birth

                                                your prayers do abort me

                                                if you only think about me

                                           you will be more imminent to me...



                                           some can banish me permanently

                                         while some make me as their shadow

                                              if you don't try to unravel me

                                                  I will be like a virus...



                                                   my entry is covertly

                                            no one knows about my strategy

                                                   I am a silent killer!!

                                              kill me before I am noxious...





          66    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="67"><![CDATA[Becoming a Parent


























                                                   Devanshu Verma
                                                     2019 - 23, CSE

                                        Saw her face, as lumpy and red as a tomato,

                                            Unwinking eyes, a nose of size micro;

                                          The best achievement I had ever earned,

                                             A part of me came into this world;

                                               Caring for her, the nights went,

                                Watching our childhood grow with us, the days were spent;

                                        The sacred bond of marriage grew stronger,

                                    Our responsibilities now turned up to our daughter;

                                          “Addiction? Drugs, alcohol?” they asked,

                                                “My child!”, with a grin I said;

                                               Becoming a parent is so lucky,

                                   Guiding them with how we grew up is such a melody;

                                     That innocent face of hers had set my worries free,

                                     It helps her to get whatever she demands from me;

                                      I wished but I knew I couldn’t let her stay forever

                                     As she grew, she had to embark on her endeavour

                                                It isn’t easy to let her go away,

                                    But the new generation must choose their own way.








                                                                                       Expressions '22     67]]></page><page Index="68"><![CDATA[Where's Mom?


























                                               Medwin Mirza A
                                                2019 - 23, ECE

                             You come back home from an exhaustive day at school,

                       to just lie down on the floor. Still not at peace yet?.......Where's mom?




                          Couldn't sleep cause the demons under the bed might get you?

                                      Need a defender? ....... Where's mom?



                                     Stomach hurts? Head dizzy? Leg cramps?

                              Hungry in the middle of the night? ....... Where's mom?




                               Couldn't find the remote? Couldn't find your books?

                                   Couldn't find happiness? ....... Where's mom?




                        Need the best cuisine from the best chef ever?...... Where's mom?




                             Need a friend? Partner? Archenemy? Advisor? Teacher?
                            A mobile-doctor? An exclusive lawyer?........Where's mom?




                                A very happy Mother’s Day to every loveable mom.

                                Okay then, about to bake a cake for Mother’s Day.

                                        Where's the flour?.......Where's mom?





          68    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="69"><![CDATA[Greed or Grace


























                                                    Himanshu Kumar
                                                2020 - 24, Mechatronics

                  I do narrate before you a story of battle.              was going to happen in the

                    A king long lived had a golden cradle                     Emperor’s premise.
                      An epitome of justice a placid one                The crater warrior behaved an

                     A brave warrior in the long war run.                army, which he commanded

                       Banished with the long old age                      But who knows his empire
                 Promised to provide a triumphant thronage                  will no sooner turn red.

                           He was blessed with two                         misfortune though doesn't
                            lovely princes golden                              awares its arrival.

                          Their excellent behaviour                    Yes, his enemy attacked he fought
                            kept the king bolden.                            for his throne's revival.

                 The elder among the duo grew courageous                  The prince was summoned
                                                                            to help him in the fight
                        Trouble for the rulers heaved

                            his destiny prestigious.                      He proved he leaned before
                                                                               his brother’s sight.
                          The singlet left was trained
                           rigorous, eyed his father                     No, mercy to the betrayers his
                                                                            glimming sword talked.
                  A perfectionist bethoven as clear as lather
                                                                      His weapon bathed with blood the
                        The elder bro kept regaining                     enemy were fiercely shocked.
                            the mysterious powers
                                                                       The treacherous day ever arrived
                    Built his empire under the supervision
                            of mysterious towers.                 But his destiny made the wounded revived.

                       The story takes a brisk turn, the
                            tale must get a remise
                      No one was going to know what





                                                                                       Expressions '22     69]]></page><page Index="70"><![CDATA[So says the satellite...


























                                                  RA. Srinethe
                                                2020 - 24, ECE

                    I see you heaving a deep sigh,            But I have also seen them stand tall,

                     Trying desperately not to cry,                 As they come out of their

                  As you look above, you look at me,                    troubles so deep.

                    Shining at you like I’m fantasy.
                                                            Life may not always be a summer’s day,


               Now there are a few things I want to say,    There is a fair share of gloom and glee,
                     This is transient, your dismay,             It is up to you to fight and stay,

                    When it looks like everything’s           Or to give in to your doubts and flee.

                             falling apart,

                It might just be for another good start.     Everyone has their time and so do you,

                                                                And now it may just not be yours,
                       There are plenty of things               Everyone has their time to shine,

                         I’ve seen and heard,                      It’s the day for the sun and

                  Apart from the chirping of crickets                   the night is mine.
                        and the songs of birds,

                 So let me fill you in with what I know,             Till then let me give you

                  Of the things that I’ve seen below.           The warmth that the sun couldn’t

                                                                    And with you, I shall pray

                  I have seen kingdoms rise and fall,              As the element of the night

                      I have seen the best weep,                      who wishes for a day.




          70    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="71"><![CDATA[Voice of my Soul


























                                                         Boomisha
                                                  2021 - 25, Chemical

                                                        People say give,

                                                              But,
                                                      Do they really give?

                                                  The way I want to see this

                                                      society still lies as a
                                                            Dream,

                                                   As this world shows me a

                                                        Different angle.
                                                   Wish to make it a ball...

                                                              But,
                                                Still exists as a two faced coin.

                                                        People say give,

                                                              But,
                                                      Do they really give?
























                                                                                       Expressions '22     71]]></page><page Index="72"><![CDATA[A
                                             rtwork























































































          72    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="73"><![CDATA[Gowtham Kanna M  2019 - 23, ECE


























































































                                                                                       Expressions '22     73]]></page><page Index="74"><![CDATA[Moncher Lucien D
                                                                                2018 - 22, EIE






          74    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="75"><![CDATA[Pugazhendy S
                                              2019 - 23, Mechanical







































































                                                                                       Expressions '22     75]]></page><page Index="76"><![CDATA[Shruthi S
                                               2019 - 23, CSE









































































          76    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="77"><![CDATA[Vetrivel M
                     2019 - 23, EEE








































































                                                                                       Expressions '22     77]]></page><page Index="78"><![CDATA[G Kishore Kannan
                                                    2021 - 25, IT








































































          78    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="79"><![CDATA[Sadhana Sri S  2021 - 25, ECE


























































































                                                                                       Expressions '22     79]]></page><page Index="80"><![CDATA[Sushma Koppada
                                             2021 - 25, EIE









































































          80    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="81"><![CDATA[Yuvarani V D
                        2021 - 25, ECE





































































                                                                                       Expressions '22     81]]></page><page Index="82"><![CDATA[G
                                              allery























































































          82    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="83"><![CDATA[Literary Club - First Annual Day










































                                           Literary Club in action






                                                                                       Expressions '22     83]]></page><page Index="84"><![CDATA[Group discussion back in 90's
















































                  Literary Club Certificates - from the pages of History





          84    Expressions '22]]></page><page Index="85"><![CDATA[Cogito, ergo sum









                                              Editorial Team






















                  Najmu Sehar Wani                      Rahul A P                     Tarun J Sherry

                      2020 - 22, Civil                2018 - 22, Civil             2018 - 22, Mechanical


                                                                                       Expressions '22     85]]></page><page Index="86"><![CDATA[EXPRESSIONS






                                                                                      '22]]></page></pages></Search>